<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<catalog>
    <book id="1">
        <title>Oven Baked Fries</title>
        <etad>45 Mins</etad>
        <rdisc>Greasyness</rdisc>
        <text>Ingredients:
        
5 pounds Yukon Gold potatoes

Vegetable or Olive oil

Sea salt

EXTRA:

Cajin or desired seasoning

Directions:

Peel and rinse the potatoes. Then cut them into sticks or into the desired shape.
Place them in a large bowl and fill the bowl with cold water. Allow them to soak for at least 2 to 3 hours. 

When you're ready to make the fries, drain off the water and dry the potatos.

In a bowl

Preheat the oven to 425 Degrees F

Sprinkle with sea salt, then place in oven for 45mins.

Picture Copyright of https://SpendWithPennies.com
Recipedo Original</text>
        <rating>1</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/ovenbakedfries.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="2">
        <title>Snicker Doodle Cookies</title>
        <etad>45 Mins</etad>
        <rdisc>Holiday Joy</rdisc>
        <text>Ingredients
2 ¾ cups all-purpose flour 
1 ½ cups white sugar 
¼ teaspoon salt 
4 tablespoons white sugar 
2 teaspoons ground cinnamon
½ cup butter, softened 
½ cup shortening 
2 eggs 
3 teaspoons vanilla extract 
2 teaspoons cream of tartar 
1 teaspoon baking soda 

Directions:

Pre-Heat the oven to 400 Degrees F, 200 Degrees C

For 3-4 Minutes Cream the butter, shortning, and sugar together. 
Mix together all of the Dry ingredients.
Add the Eggs
Add half of the dry ingredients together with the butter and.
Gradually add more of the dry ingredients.
shape into balls 

Bake for 7-11mins, Remove immediately.

Enjoy!

Recipedo Original</text>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/Snickerdoodles.jpeg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="3">
        <title>Pineapple Upside Down Cake</title>
        <etad>1hour</etad>
        <rdisc>Yummmm</rdisc>
        <text>Ingredients:
            
3/8 cup butter
1 cup packed brown sugar
1 can (20 oz) pineapple slices in juice 
1 jar (6 oz) maraschino cherries
1 box Premix Yellow Cake Mix (and its ingredients) or Homemade Recipe Equivalent

Directions:

When making the batter subsitute water with the pineapple juice, If needed ad water to the juice to equal the amount of water needed for cake batter.

Pre-Heat the Oven to 350 Degrees F (Dark Non-Stick Bakers, 325)

In the pan add the butter and melt it in the oven.

After melted pull out of the oven and sprinkle the brown sugar on top of the melted butter.

Gentely Add the pineapple slices to the brown sugar. Then add the Cherries in the holes of the pine apples.

Pour batter on the pineapple and brown sugar.

bake for 45 to 50 minutes (47 to 55 minutes for dark or nonstick pan) or until toothpick comes out clean.

Using a knife cut the side of the pan to ensure the cake come out clean.

Recipedo Original</text>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/pineappleupsidedowncake.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="4">
        <title>BarBQ Sauce</title>
        <etad>45 mins</etad>
        <rdisc>Adaptability</rdisc>
        <text>Ingredients:
        
        2 Cups Brown Sugar
        3 Cups of Ketchup
        2 Teaspoons of Liquid Smoke
        2 Tablespoons of Molassis
        2 Teaspoons Cumin
        1/4 Cup Butter
        
Directions:
        
    In a pan Add the butter,Cumin, Brown Sugar and Molassis to a pan. 
        
    On a low heat simmer the ingrediants together until they start to bubble.
        Add the Ketchup and simmer until thick.
        
    Add the Liquid smoke and stir until well incorperated.
        
    Note: with this recipe you can add ingredients like fruit or spices! even your favorite hot sauce!
        
    Photo Credit: https://www.lecremedelacrumb.com/dallas-bbq-sauce/

Recipedo Original</text>
        <rating>4</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/bbqsauce.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="5">
        <title>Meat Loaf</title>
        <etad>1 hour</etad>
        <rdisc>Meaty Goodness</rdisc>
        <text>Ingredients:
1lbs Ground Beef
2 TBSP Cumin
1 TBSP Garlic Powder
1 TBSP Onion Powder
1 Cup Ketchup
1/2 Cup Chopped Onion
1/2 Cup Chopped Peppers
2 Eggs
2/3 Cup Bread crumbs

Pre-Heat the Oven to 375 Degrees F

Mix all Ingredients in to a bowl, Making sure it is well combined.

In a bread pan make sure to form to the pan.

Add Ketchup to the top of the loaf.

Put into the oven for 55 Mins, or until fully cooked.

Image Copyright Food Network - Recipe not Shown
Recipedo Original</text>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/meatloaf.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="6">
        <title>Beef Stroganoff</title>
        <etad>1 hour</etad>
        <rdisc>Creamy Beefy</rdisc>
        <text>Ingredients
2 tablespoons butter
1 package (8 oz) sliced baby portabella mushrooms
1 cup chopped onions
2 cloves garlic, finely chopped
1 lb lean (at least 80%) ground beef
1 1/2 cups Progresso™ beef-flavored broth (from 32-oz carton)
1 tablespoon Worcestershire sauce
3/4 teaspoon salt
1/4 teaspoon pepper
1/4 cup Gold Medal™ all-purpose flour
1 cup sour cream
6 cups cooked egg noodles
Chopped Italian (flat-leaf) parsley, if desired

Directions:
In 10-inch nonstick skillet, melt butter over medium heat. Cook mushrooms, onions and garlic in butter 5 to 7 minutes, stirring occasionally, until tender. Remove from skillet to small bowl; set aside.

Increase heat to medium-high. In same skillet, cook beef 5 to 7 minutes, stirring frequently, until no longer pink; drain. Stir in 1 cup of the beef broth, the Worcestershire sauce, salt and pepper; heat to boiling. Beat flour and remaining 1/2 cup beef broth with whisk until incorporated; stir into beef mixture. Add mushroom mixture; return to boiling, and stir constantly about 1 minute or until mixture thickens. Remove from heat; stir in sour cream.

Serve with cooked egg noodles. Garnish with parsley.
Image Copyright damndelicious.net - Recipe not Shown, Recipe Copyright Betty Crocker</text>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/beefstroganoff.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="7">
        <title>Taco Meat</title>
        <etad>1 hour</etad>
        <rdisc>Meaty Goodness</rdisc>
        <text>Ingredients:
1/2 Pound Ground Beef
1/2 Pound Ground Pork
1 TBSP sea salt
1/8 Cup Olive Oil
6 Tsp Cumin
3 Tsp Paprika
3 Tsp Cayenne
2 Tsp Chilli Powder
5 Tsp Garlic Powder
5 Tsp Onion Powder
1/2 Cup Chopped Onion

In a sauce pan, add the onion, salt, and olive oil. Cook until translucent.

add the meat and spices. Simmer on a medium heat.

Once all the ingredents are well in coreperated cook until browned.

Image Copyright countrysidecravings.com - Recipe not Shown
Recipedo Original</text>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/tacomeat.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="8">
        <title>Juicy Meat</title>
        <etad>1 hour</etad>
        <rdisc>Juiciness</rdisc>
        <text>Ingredients
2 Lbs Desired Meat
Seasoning of Choice
1 Cup of Lemon Juice or  3/4 Vineger

Adding this to your meat will lock in the juices and seal the flavor in.

Image Copyright Delish.com - Image not of Recipe
Recipedo Original</text>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/grilledchicken.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="9">
        <title>Fried Potatoes</title>
        <etad>1 hour</etad>
        <rdisc>Fried Goodness</rdisc>
        <text>Ingredients:

2 Pounds of Yukon Gold Potatos
3 Cups Salted Butter
Pepper
1 Onion
1 Bell Pepper
2 Cups of Water

Directions:

In a large frying pan. add 1 Cup of Salted butter and 2 cups of water  to the pan. Heat until butter is melted.

Add the potatoes to the water and cook until water is gone. its important not to stur!

While the potatoes are cooking add the peppers and onions with 1/2 Cup of butter to a skillet and caramelize. 

after water is gone add the onions and peppers to the pan with the remaining butter.

Fry until crispy.

Image Copyright Deep South Dish - Image not of Recipe
Recipedo Original</text>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/friedpotatoes.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="10">
        <title>Crunchy Chicken Tacos</title>
        <etad>1 hour</etad>
        <rdisc>Crunch</rdisc>
        <text>Celebrate taco Tuesday with these Crunch Chicken Tacos. Shredded lettuce and crispy taco shells bring the snap to these Crunchy Chicken Tacos great for any occasion. Top with your favorite salsa and sour cream.

What You Need

4 flour tortillas (6 inch)
1 lb. boneless skinless chicken breasts, cut into bite-size pieces 1/2 tsp. ground cumin
1/2 tsp. chili powder
2 tsp. oil
1/2 cup chopped tomato
1 cup shredded iceberg lettuce
1/2 cup KRAFT Mexican Style Finely Shredded Four Cheese

Heat oven to 425°F.

Crumble 4 sheets of foil to form 4 (2-inch) balls. Fold tortillas in half; place one foil ball inside each folded tortilla to resemble a taco shell. Place on two baking sheets. Bake 7 to 8 min. or until golden brown. Cool on baking sheets 5 min. or until taco shells are crisp. Remove and discard foil.

Meanwhile, toss chicken with spices. Heat oil in medium skillet on medium-high heat. Add chicken; cook 5 to 6 min. or until chicken is done.

Spoon chicken mixture into taco shells; top with remaining ingredients.

Recipe and Image Copyright KraftHeinz</text>
        <rating>3</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/crunchychickentacos.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="11">
        <title>Garlic Bread Mac &amp; Cheese</title>
        <etad>1 hour</etad>
        <rdisc>Cheesy</rdisc>
        <text>Ingredients:
2 Cups of Cheddar Cheese
1 Cup Sharp white Cheddar
2 Cups of Whole milk
Salt / Pepper
8 Cloves of garlic
1/2 Cup Flour
2 Cups salted butter
1/2 Cup of Butter Crackers
4 Cups of Noodles of choice

Directions:

In a pot add 2 tps of salt to water. Boil then add the noodles. Cook Noodles until a fork can puncure them. Immediately strainwater. After completely straining water, put noodles in pan with cold water. And strain again. This will insure the noodles stop cooking.

In a sauce pan, add 2 cups of salted butter and garlic, melt butter and roast the garlic in the butter. 

Once garlic butter has browned add the flour and mix until well combined. cook until browned. 

add milk to roux and mix until it is well combined. add Cheese and stir until melted.

In a glass pan add the noodles and garlic cheese sauce. Sprinkle butter cracker crumbs on top and bake in the oven at 350 for 30 Mins.


Image Copyright Mom on Timeout - Image not of Recipe
Recipedo Original</text>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/macncheese.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="12">
        <title>Chicken Noodle Soup</title>
        <etad>1 hour</etad>
        <rdisc>Meaty Goodness</rdisc>
        <text>INGREDIENTS:

2 tablespoons unsalted butter
1 onion, diced
2 carrots, peeled and diced
2 stalks celery, diced
3 cloves garlic, minced
8 cups chicken stock
2 bay leaves
Kosher salt freshly ground black pepper, to taste
2 1/2 pounds bone-in, skinless chicken breasts
2 1/2 cups wide egg noodles
2 tablespoons chopped fresh parsley leaves
2 tablespoons chopped fresh dill
1 tablespoon freshly squeezed lemon juice, or more, to taste

DIRECTIONS:

Melt butter in a large stockpot or Dutch oven over medium heat. Add onion, carrots and celery. Cook, stirring occasionally, until tender, about 3-4 minutes. Stir in garlic until fragrant, about 1 minute.
Whisk in chicken stock and bay leaves; season with salt and pepper, to taste. Add chicken and bring to boil; reduce heat and simmer, covered, until the chicken is cooked through, about 30-40 minutes. Remove chicken and let cool before dicing into bite-size pieces, discarding bones.
Stir in chicken and pasta and cook until tender, about 6-7 minutes.
Remove from heat; stir in parsley, dill and lemon juice; season with salt and pepper, to taste.
Serve immediately.

Recipe Copyright Damndelicious.net</text>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/chickennoodlesoup.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="13">
        <title>Meatballs</title>
        <etad>1 hour</etad>
        <rdisc>Meaty Goodness</rdisc>
        <text>Ingredients:
1 Pound Ground Beef
1 Pound Ground Itailian Sausage
3.5 Cups of Bread Crumbs
3 Large Eggs

Directions:

In a bowl mix wet and dry ingredients.

Roll into ball shape.

Brown in pan until all sides of the meat balls are browned.

Place meat balls in oven at 375 Degrees and back for 25 Minuates

Image Copyright Cooking Classy - Image not of Recipe
Recipedo Original</text>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/meatballs.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="14">
        <title>Portuguese Chourico and Kale Soup</title>
        <etad>30 Minutes</etad>
        <rdisc>Heartiness</rdisc>
        <text>Ingredients:
2 tablespoons (2 turns around the pan) extra- virgin olive oil
3 medium white waxy potatoes, like yukon golds, peeled and diced
2 medium onions, chopped
4 to 6 cloves garlic, chopped
2 bay leaves, fresh or dried
1 pound kale, coarsely chopped
Coarse salt and pepper
1 (15-ounce) can garbanzos (chick peas), drained and rinsed
1 can diced tomatoes
1 pound diced chourico, casing removed 1 quart chicken broth
Warm, crusty bread

Heat oil in a deep pot over medium high heat. Add potatoes and onions,
cover and cook 5 minutes, stirring occasionally.

Add garlic, bay leaves, and kale to the pot. Cover pot and wilt greens 2
minutes. Season with salt and pepper.
Add beans, tomatoes, chourico, and broth to the pot and bring soup to a full boil. Reduce heat back to medium and cook 5 to 10 minutes longer or until potatoes are tender.

Serve soup with hunks of crusty bread and butter.

Cook's Note: If you are in Mystic, ask for cherise (phonetic pronunciation), if you want to sample the chourico.

Copyright Food Network</text>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/portuguesekalesoup.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="15">
        <title>Roasted Garlic Bread</title>
        <etad>1 hr 20 min</etad>
        <rdisc>Crispy</rdisc>
        <text>Ingredients:
1 head garlic
3 tablespoons extra-virgin olive oil
Kosher salt and freshly ground black pepper One 12-inch baguette, split lengthwise
2 tablespoons grated Parmesan
2 tablespoons coarsely chopped fresh parsley

Directions

Preheat the oven to 400 degrees F.

Cut the top third off the head of garlic, exposing the tops of the garlic cloves. Put on a piece of aluminum foil, drizzle with 1 tablespoon of the oil and sprinkle with 1/4 teaspoon each salt and pepper. Wrap tightly and roast until the cloves are golden brown and very soft, about 45 minutes; cool slightly.

Unwrap the garlic and pour any garlic-flavored oil from the foil into a small bowl; squeeze the roasted cloves into the same bowl, discarding the papery shells. Add the remaining 2 tablespoons oil and mash with a fork until smooth; season with additional salt and pepper.

Put the bread halves on a baking sheet and evenly spread with the roasted garlic mixture. Top with the Parmesan and a few grinds of pepper. Bake until the bread is toasted and the cheese is melted, about 10 minutes. Sprinkle with parsley and cut into pieces.

Copyright Food Network</text>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/roastedgarlicbread.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="16">
        <title>Apple Sauce</title>
        <etad>55 Minutes</etad>
        <rdisc>Pre-School Nostalgia factor</rdisc>
        <text>Ingredients:

4 pounds of apples (about 8 to 10 apples, depending on the size), peeled, cored, and quartered (use apples varieties that are good for cooking such as Granny Smith, Pippin, Gravenstein, Mcintosh, Fuji, Jonathan, Jonagold, or Golden Delicious)
2 strips of lemon peel (use a vegetable peeler to strip the zest only, not the pith)
3 tablespoons lemon juice or apple cider vinegar (more or less to taste)
1/2 teaspoon ground cinnamon
Up to 1/2 cup of white sugar (can sub half of the white sugar with brown sugar)
1 cup of water
1/2 teaspoon of salt

Boil peeled, cored, quartered apples with lemon, cinnamon, sugar, salt in 1 cup water:
Place the peeled, cored, and quartered apples into a large pot. Add the strips of lemon peel, the lemon juice or vinegar, cinnamon, sugar, water and salt. (You might want to start with half the sugar at this point and add more to taste later.)

Bring to a boil on high heat, then lower the temperature, cover the pot, and maintain a low simmer for 15-20 minutes, until the apples are completely tender and cooked through.

Remove lemon peels, mash the cooked apples:
Once the apples are cooked through, remove the pot from the heat. Remove the lemon peels.

Use a potato masher to mash the cooked apples in the pot to make a chunky applesauce. For a smoother applesauce you can either run the cooked apples through a food mill, or purée them using a stick blender or a standing blender. (If you use a standing blender, do small batches and do not fill the blender bowl more than halfway.)

If the applesauce is too thick, add more water to thin it out.

If not sweet enough, add more sugar to taste. If too sweet, add more lemon juice.

This applesauce is delicious either hot or chilled. It pairs well with pork chops for savory dishes, it's terrific with cottage cheese as a snack or light lunch, and it's great with vanilla ice cream or yogurt.

Freezes well and will last at least a year in a cold freezer. If you freeze it, make sure to allow enough headroom in your jar for expansion. At least an inch.



Copyright Simply Recipes</text>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/applesauce.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="17">
        <title>Chocolate Chunk Cookies</title>
        <etad>30 Minutes</etad>
        <rdisc>Chocolate Overload</rdisc>
        <text>Ingredients:
butter: unsalted or salted will work! but if you’re using salted, reduce the salt called for in the dry ingredients by 1/4 teaspoon.
sugar: you’ll use a combination of brown sugar and granulated sugar (also known as white sugar). light brown sugar or dark brown sugar may be used.
eggs: two large ones, at room temperature!
vanilla extract: just a dash will enhance all the other flavors in this recipe.
flour: all-purpose!
salt: to balance out the flavors.
baking soda: helps leaven the cookie dough, which in turn gives us soft and chewy cookies.
and finally, chocolate chunks! you know i’m a lindt lover, so i their 70% chocolate bars. but use your favorite brand! and yes, you can even use chocolate chips, instead.

Directions:
For the Brown Butter:
Place the butter in a small saucepan over medium-high heat and cook for 3 to 4 minutes – stirring almost constantly – until the butter has browned. Pour the brown butter into a heatproof bowl, being sure to scrape all of the "toasted" bits into the bowl as well. Place the bowl in the refrigerator for 1 hour, or until the butter is at room temperature. You’ll know the butter is at room temperature when you press a finger into the top and it makes a slight indentation. It should be solid but soft.

Once the butter is at room temperature, you're ready to get baking!

Preheat your oven to 375 degrees (F).

For the Best Ever Chocolate Chunk Cookies:
In a medium-sized bowl whisk together the flour, baking soda, and salt; set aside.
In a large bowl using a handheld electric mixer, or in the bowl of a stand mixer fitted with the paddle attachment, combine both sugars, vanilla, and browned butter; cream on medium-speed until light and fluffy; about 2 minutes. Add in the eggs, one at a time, beating for 15 seconds after each addition. Turn mixer off. Using a wooden spoon or sturdy rubber spatula, gently fold in the flour, stirring only until the flour begins to disappear. Fold in the chocolate chunks.

Roll 3 tablespoon sized scoops of dough between your palms to form a ball (they should be big; almost a 1/4 cup), then place on prepared sheet (make sure to leave enough room in between each cookie for inevitable spreading). Continue this process until all the dough has been rolled. Place baking sheets in preheated oven, one at a time, and bake for 9 to 10 minutes, or until golden at the edges but still soft in the middle. Repeat with all cookie dough. Let cookies cool for 10 minutes on the baking sheet before transferring to a wire wrack to cool completely.

Copyright Baker by Nature</text>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/chocolatechunkcookies.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="18">
        <title>Italian Oven Roasted Vegetables</title>
        <etad>1 hour</etad>
        <rdisc>Italian Flavor</rdisc>
        <text>In this Italian-inspired roasted vegetables recipe, I use a combination of bright, and colorful veggies and mushrooms, tossed in extra virgin olive oil and a simple seasoning with some of my favorite Italian flavors. Here's what you'll need:

Ingredients:
Vegetables &amp; Mushrooms: zucchini (or summer squash), bella mushrooms, and baby potatoes (or diced gold potatoes)
Tomatoes: I like Camparie tomatoes here because they tend to be on the sweeter side. Grape tomatoes or cherry tomatoes are great too!
Seasoning: Kosher salt, fresh garlic, oregano and fresh thyme.
Quality Extra Virgin Olive Oil

Directions:
Set the oven on high heat. We chatted about this earlier but it bears repeating, if you want the best roasted veggies set the oven anywhere between 400 to 450 degrees F, depending on what vegetables you're working with. Here I went for 425 degrees F and roasted the veggies on the middle rack. Because potatoes take a bit more time, they went in first for 10 minutes before adding the rest of the vegetables. 
Cut the vegetables into similar size pieces. This will help everything cook evenly and at the same time (but see my note on potatoes below). 
Flavor the Vegetables well. One important thing is to make sure the vegetables are evenly seasoned. To do that, place the already cut vegetables in a large bowl, add salt and pepper and other spices of your choice (I used oregano and thyme). I also love adding fresh garlic, and the garlic roasts, it will mellow and add sweetness. Give everything a good toss with the help of a little extra virgin olive oil. 
Don't Skimp on the olive oil! Toss your veggies with a good-tasting extra virgin oil. Use enough of the oil to coat the vegetables well and give them a glossy look, but don't use too much that you end up with excess oil in the bottom of your bowl. I would say somewhere around 2 tablespoons. Toss to make sure everything is well combined and the vegetables are well-coated with the seasoning. When ready, transfer the vegetables to your baking pan or baking sheet.
Use a heavy, drak baking pan or baking dish for roasting. The dark coating helps the veggies brown well. I often use a cast iron baking dish (affiliate link), the added benefit of cast iron is that it provides even, steady heat.
Roast in stages if you need to (potatoes need more time than zucchini). Because potatoes will take a bit longer than things like zucchini and tomatoes in this roasted vegetables recipe, I went ahead and put the baby potatoes in the oven for a good 10 minutes before adding the rest of the vegetables. 
Do not crowd the pan. For best texture and flavor, make sure your veggies are well-spread in one single layer on your baking pan or dish. If you need to, use two pans. Crowding the veggies will result in steaming them rather than roasting.

Copyright themediterraneandish.com</text>
        <rating>4</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/roastedveggies.jpg</image>
    </book>
    <book id="19">
        <title>Lemon Pepper Salmon</title>
        <etad>1 hour</etad>
        <rdisc>Meaty Goodness</rdisc>
        <text>Ingredients
Salmon. You can make baked salmon with the skin on or off. I prefer my lemon pepper salmon with the skin on for ease (it helps lock in extra moisture).

The skin peels off easily after your salmon is cooked, so you can remove it before serving or just eat around it on your plate. That said if you prefer your baked salmon without skin, you can either select it that way at the grocery store. If it doesn’t come that way to begin with, the seafood will often remove it for you.

It’s important to look for high-quality, wild-caught varieties of salmon. Where I shop, that usually means coho, sockeye, or king—most of the time I choose coho or sockeye (king is delicious but super pricey). Try to avoid farm-raised, fatty Atlantic salmon. They are often fed an artificial diet and contain less nutrients. This type of salmon is typically more watery as well, which can cause your salmon dish to become mushy.

Lemon. While I always enjoy lemon with my fish, in this version it SHINES. The recipes uses both the lemon zest and juice for max citrus impact.
Black Pepper. The citrus flavors are truly elevated by the inclusion of black pepper. It adds a nice kick of flavor to the salmon without making it spicy. (Another place you can find this killer combo: Lemon Pepper Wings).

Herbs. For a bit of extra color and freshness. You can use anything you have growing in your garden or what looks best at your grocery store. Another bonus of cooking with herbs and lemon: they add incredible fresh flavor to this dish without any extra calories. No herbs on hand? In this recipe, you can omit them. The lemon and pepper still carry the flavor.

Olive Oil. Olive oil adds healthy fats, keep the salmon moist, and ensure it bakes perfectly.

Directions:
First, place your salmon on a plate and allow to come to room temperature. This will help it cook evenly all the way though.

Next, grab a large piece of aluminum foil, and place it on your baking sheet. Spray lightly with nonstick spray, and lay down a row of your fresh herbs (I used thyme) and lemon slices.Lemon pepper salmon in aluminum foil with lemon and fresh herbs
Take your piece of salmon, and lay it over the herbs and lemon. Top it with lemon zest, lemon juice, and salt and pepper. Flavor baby!

Now, you’re ready to seal up the packet of yummy flavors and salmon. Make sure there’s enough to fully cover the salmon piece, leaving some room for air to circulate.
Then, move your baking sheet with the foil packet to the oven and bake at 375 degrees F for 15-20 minutes, until the salmon flakes easily with a fork.

Easy and perfectly cooked lemon pepper salmon in aluminum foil with skin on

When you’re ready to serve, top your salmon with additional fresh herbs (I added some extra thyme) or lemon juice. Voilà!

Copyright Well Plated by Erin</text>
        <rating>5</rating>
        <image>https://a.adxstudios.com/recipedo/gallery/lemonpeppersalmon.jpg</image>
    </book>
</catalog>